Inventory of the Harry Roscoe Snyder papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Arabian American Oil Company, Education and Arab Training File, 1941-1998 (Boxes 14-24)
  - College of Petroleum and Minerals, 1950-1987 (Boxes 22-24)
    - Memoranda, 1965-1971 (Folder 24: 2-4)
    - Minutes from meetings regarding vocational secondary school, 1966-1967 (Folder 24: 5-6)
    - Newsletters, clippings, and other printed matter, 1965-1981 (Folder 24: 7)
    - Notes, 1968-1970 (Folder 24: 8)
    - Questionnaire, 1967 (Folder 24: 9)
    - Textbook order forms, 1971-1972 (Folder 24: 10)
    - Yearbooks, 1968-1969 (Folder 24: 11-12)
    - Miscellany, 1950-1975, undated (Folder 24: 13)
- Educational Consulting File, 1961-1983 (Boxes 24-30)
  Includes reports, architectural records, program proposals, clippings, schedules, correspondence, notes, and contracts, arranged by client name, then chronologically.
  - General, 1975-1978, undated (Folder 24: 14)
    Includes booklet advertising company, clippings about higher education in Saudi Arabia, and a datebook logging expenses from consulting trips.
  - Civil aviation and manpower training materials, 1961-1983 (Folder 25: 1-11)
  - King Abdulaziz Military Academy materials, 1974-1976 (Folder 25: 12-16)
  - King Abdulaziz Military Academy materials (cont'd.), 1974-1976 (Folder 26: 1-6)
  - Girls University of Riyadh materials, 1975 (Folder 26: 7-10)
  - Girls University of Riyadh materials (cont'd.), 1975 (Folder 27: 1-5)
  - University of Riyadh materials, 1975-1980 (Folder 27: 6-12)
    Includes mostly program proposals.
  - University of Riyadh materials (cont'd.), 1975-1980 (Folder 28: 1-10)
  - University of Riyadh materials (cont'd.), 1975-1980 (Folder 29: 1-4)
  - Imam Mohammed Ibn Saud Islamic University project correspondence, 1976 (Folder 29: 5)
  - King Faisal University materials, 1976-1981 (Folder 29: 6-13)
  - King Faisal University materials (cont'd.), 1976-1981 (Folder 30: 1-4)
  - International School, Riyadh correspondence and notes, 1980 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Royal Saudi Naval Academy-Jubail reports and memoranda, 1980 (Folder 30: 6-9)
- Graduate Coursework and Dissertation, 1953-1984 (Boxes 30-32)
  Consists of essays, outlines, clippings, dissertation, and notes, arranged by title chronologically; dissertation and related materials are filed at the end. Folder titles correspond with course title or project.
  - "Muslim Religion and Philosophy,", 1953 (Folder 30: 10)
  - "History and Civilization of Ancient Near East,", 1953 (Folder 30: 11)
  - "Man and Culture,", 1953 (Folder 31: 1)
  - "Critical Issues in Education,", 1955 (Folder 31: 2)
  - "Philosophy of Education,", 1955 July-August (Folder 31: 3)
  - "Anthropology and Education,", 1955 July-August (Folder 31: 4)
  - Manual for education course, 1955 October (Folder 31: 5)
  - "Education and Underdeveloped Areas,", 1955 October - 1956 January (Folder 31: 6)
  - "Curriculum and Instruction in Higher Education,", 1955-1956 (Folder 31: 7)
  - "Intellectual Foundations of Modern Education,", 1955-1956 (Folder 31: 8)
  - "Teachers for Saudi Arabia," term paper, 1956 January (Folder 31: 9)
  - Community College Education for Saudi Arabia, dissertation, 1955-1984 (Box 32)
    - Research materials, 1955-1965 (Folder 32: 1-2)
      Includes duplicates of Aramco reports and correspondence.
    - Writing plans, 1956 May (Folder 32: 3)
    - Admissions paperwork, 1956-1963 (Folder 32: 4)
    - Notes, 1962-1963 (Folder 32: 5)
    - Working draft, 1963 June (Folder 32: 6)
    - Final working draft, 1963 (Folder 32: 7-8)
      Includes original photographs.
    - 'Abdul 'Aziz Ibn Turki correspondence, 1984 (Folder 32: 9)
- Subject File, 1943-1986 (Boxes 33-36)
  Consists of clippings, correspondence, writings, booklets, and monograph, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Aerial bombing of Libya, 1986 (Folder 33: 1)
  - American Graduate School of International Management, 1975-1981 (Folder 33: 2)
  - American School for Boys, Baghdad, 1947 (Folder 33: 3)
  - American University of Beirut, 1953-1971 (Folder 33: 4-5)
    - General, 1964-1971 (Folder 33: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1966 (Folder 33: 5)
  - American University of Beirut Alumni Association, 1981-1984 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Americans for Fairness in the Middle East, 1970-1974 (Folder 33: 7)
  - Americans for Middle East Understanding, 1973-1974 (Folder 33: 8)
  - Dinsmore, Lee, 1975 (Folder 33: 9)
  - F.D.R. Meets Ibn Saud by William Alfred Eddy, 1977-1978 (Folder 33: 10)
  - Foreign area studies in the United States, 1943-1956 (Folder 33: 11)
  - International College, Beirut, 1959-1983 (Folder 33: 12)
  - Malone, Joseph J., 1974-1984 (Folder 33: 13-16)
    - Clippings, 1984 (Folder 33: 13)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Folder 33: 14)
    - Writings, 1974-1982 (Folder 33: 15-16)
  - Middlebury College, 1981-1984 (Folder 33: 17)
  - Middle East education, 1944-1961 (Folder 34: 1)
  - Middle East Institute conferences, 1972-1973 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Muslim-Christian cooperation, 1956 (Folder 34: 3)
  - Near East culture and society, 1947-1950 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Said B. Himadeh Chair of Business Administration, 1965-1967 (Folder 34: 5)
  - Saudi Arabia, 1949-1983 (Boxes 34-35)
    - General, circa 1958-1967 (Folder 34: 6)
    - Architecture, 1975-1983 (Folder 34: 7)
    - Education, 1949-1975 (Folder 34: 8-11)
      - General, 1949-1975 (Folder 34: 8-9)
      - Girls, 1962-1965 (Folder 34: 10)
      - Industrial, 1954-1964 (Folder 34: 11)
    - Foreign relations, 1951, undated (Folder 34: 12)
    - Oil crisis, 1967 (Folder 34: 13)
    - Oil embargo, 1972-1975 (Folder 35: 1-2)
    - Oil exploration, 1958-1961 (Folder 35: 3)
    - Urban development, 1968-1974 (Folder 35: 4)
  - Speed reading, undated (Folder 35: 5)
  - Teachers College, Columbia University, 1975 (Folder 35: 6)
  - Votrakon Project, 1976-1977 (Folder 35: 7-10)
  - Uniied Arabic alphabet, 1951-1956 (Folder 35: 11)
  - U.S.-Palestine relations, late 1940s (Folder 35: 12)
  - Viola, Joy Winkie, 1982-1983 (Folder 35: 13-15)
  - Viola, Joy Winkie (cont'd.), 1982-1983 (Folder 36: 1)
- Photographs, 1930s-1971, undated (Box 36)
  Contains prints, postcards, and negatives, arranged by subject, then chronologically.
  - Harry Roscoe Snyder, 1930s-1966, undated (Box-folder 36: 2-6)
    - At University of Baghdad with Near East College Association, undated (Folder 36: 2)
      Also pictured are Herbert Hoover, Lowell Thomas, and Mrs. Calvin Staudt.
    - In military uniform, at graduation ceremonies, visiting schools in Holland, and seated with King Saud, 1930s-1966, undated (Folder 36: 3-5)
    - At openings of schools and leading tours, 1952-1965 (Folder 36: 6)
  - Schools, classrooms, and instructors in Saudi Arabia, undated (Folder 36: 7-8)
  - Aramco public relations style photographs of Dhahran, undated (Folder 36: 9)
  - Woman on a motorcycle in Sudan, 1940 (Folder 36: 10)
  - Male students in Saudi Arabia, Lebanon, and Syria, 1940-1971, undated (Folder 36: 11)
  - Postcards depicting camels and people in Kuwait and Jordan; aerial views of Abadan, Iran, 1947-1954 (Folder 36: 12)
  - Arab League Education Conference, 1955 February (Folder 36: 13)
  - 12th convention of the Organization of Arab Students in the United States, 1963 (Folder 36: 14)
  - Aramco Saudi scholarship reception in Beirut, 1965 (Folder 36: 15)
- Oversize Materials, 1940-1974, undated (Boxes 36-38)
  Consists of maps, posters, charts, photographs, album, and booklet.
  - Maps of Saudi Arabia published by the U.S. Geological Survey, 1956-1963 (Folder 36: 16-27)
  - Album from the first graduation at the College of Petroleum and Minerals, 1972 (Box 37)
  - Geographic and blueprint maps of Saudi Arabia, India, French Indochina, and Iran, 1940-1963, undated (Box 38)
  - Photographs of dinners for King Saud and Saudi Arabian officials hosted by Aramco in the United States, 1940s (Box 38)
  - Harry Roscoe Snyder in group portrait at Essex House, 1946 December 7 (Box 38)
  - Photograph of scale model of CPM or Dhahran camp, 1950s (Box 38)
  - Transparencies depicting a barasti compound, 1949 May (Box 38)
  - Aramco public relations posters, 1950s (Box 38)
  - Curricula of schools in the Eastern Province of Saudi Arabia, 1959-1961 (Box 38)
  - Chart highlighting the ministries, principal directorates, and other important agencies of the Saudi Arabian Government, 1963 April 1 (Box 38)
  - Statistics issued by the Saudi Arabian Ministry of Education, 1974 (Box 38)
    2 copies.
  - "Saudia Training Academy" program proposal booklet, 1977 September (Box 38)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1944-1945 (Box 36)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 February release of records, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 36: 28)
    Memorandum from Clayton Bissell, Major General, Assistant Chief of Staff, G-2, to Chief of the Policy Staff, subject: "Reorganization of the Military Intelligence Division, W.D.G.S.," 10 May 1944.
    Memorandum from Clayton Bissell, Major General, Assistant Chief of Staff, G-2, to Chief of the Military Intelligence Service, subject: "Military Intelligence Service," 10 May 1944.
    Memoranda from Robert H. Siler, Adjutant General, to Officers Involved, through Commanding Officers Concerned, subject: "Orders," 10 March 1945 [relates to Snyder being assigned to the U.S. Military Mission to Saudi Arabia].
    Memoranda from Robert H. Siler, Adjutant General, to Officers Involved, subject: "Movement Orders," 11 March 1945.